"01_01a" "  INTERNAL H.U.D.:\nInitializing H.U.D. personal interface.\nCurrent implant linked to Command & Control.\nIn communication with Commander Horst."
"01_01b" "  ARMSTRONG: Did they kill Horst? Damn Velians! He was the\nbest C.O. a roughneck could wish for. I better get to the lower\ndecks. It's the only way to the shuttle bay. First, I'm gonna need\na key card and a more powerful weapon.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nFind a key card to access the lower deck and service rooms."
"01_01c" "  ARMSTRONG: Damn, I didn't expect the Velians to swarm so\nmuch! And some of them have deadly new silent weapon\ntechnology. I have to go through the reactor to the lower levels.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nReach the lift leading to the freight and reactor modules."
"01_01d" " "

"01_02a" "  HORST: Armstrong! I'm alive. A Velian witch shot me, but I\ndecapitated her. Engineer Robson noticed the reactor has shut\ndown. You'll have to re-start it manually, so the last of the\nescape pods can leave. Then meet me and Robson on the bridge!\n  ARMSTRONG: Yes sir!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nCollect 3 key cards and head down the lift to the reactor."
"01_02b" "  HORST: You're a damn fine soldier, Armstrong. You made it this\nfar. Now you've got to restart the reactor so we can launch\nthose escape pods! There should be a console somewhere nearby.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nGet the reactor back on-line."
"01_02c" "  HORST: The security lockdown closed off all the rooms on\nsub-level 2. That means you can't get to the main access lift.\n  ARMSTRONG: No problem, sir. I think I know where the bypass\nswitch is.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nUnlock the rooms on sub-level 2."
"01_02d" "  ARMSTRONG: This room brings back memories. The chief engineer\nhad a birthday party in here. Rolik got drunk and fell down the\nlift shaft, the idiot. Captain Minerva took all her clothes off\nand hung from that pipe like a monkey. Good times... all gone now.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nGet to the access lift."

"01_03a" "  ARMSTRONG: Commander, I'm on my way. I have to go through\nthe armory, so I'll pick up some new weaponry while I'm here.\n  HORST: Hurry, Armstrong! I'm not sure how much longer we can\nhold out here. We're about to launch the last escape pod. I'm\nputting my daughter onboard.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nFind a way to open the armored hatch."
"01_03b" "  ROBSON: Hello? Sergeant Armstrong? This is Robson. I'm on the\nbridge with Commander Horst. It looks like there are a couple\nof armored space-suits in your vicinity. If you can get to one,\nit'll even up the odds against the Velians.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nGain access to the armored space-suit."
"01_03c" "  HORST: No! It can't be! I've just heard... there was an ambush.\nThose Velian monsters grabbed my daughter and the other\nsurvivors. They took her aboard one of their ships! Oh god, what\nif they turn her into... No, it's unthinkable!\n  ARMSTRONG: Keep it together, Commander. I'm almost there.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nMake your way to the bridge."

"01_04a" "  ARMSTRONG: Robson, I've got the keycard, I'll be there soon.\n  HORST: Armstrong, Engineer Robson just exploded. Damn those\nVelians! Oh hell... more are coming through!\n  ARMSTRONG: Hold on sir! I'm almost there!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nMake your way to the bridge."
"01_04b" " "
"01_04c" "  INTERNAL H.U.D.:\nNo other humans on-board.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nLeave the Varyag Cruiser on the escape shuttle."
"01_04d" "  ROBSON: Sorry sergeant. We had to lock the main hatch,\nthought it would keep the Velians out, but they came through\nanother way. The commander is fist-fighting with one of their\nmaintenance robots right now. Yes! He just ripped off its arms!\nYou should be to find an access card in the officers' lounge.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nFind a key card to open the main hatch."

"02_01a" "  ARMSTRONG: The Commander's dead. He was like a father to me\nand the crew. He was the best of us!\nSo they tractored me into their space station. Doesn't matter.\nThe other escape pods made it and damn, I've got a score to\nsettle with these Velian scum!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nFind a way out from the lower deck of the hangar."
"02_01b" "  ARMSTRONG: All right Armstrong, calm down. You can't kill\nthem all by yourself. What would Commander Horst do? I know.\nHe'd put a call in to main base. I can't rightly free the enslaved\ncolonists when I'm trapped on this space station. If I can get\nto the docks there should be a sub-space communicator.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nFind an entry to the docks section."

"02_02a" "  ARMSTRONG: Okay, I'm at the docks. If I remember the design\nschematics correctly then the comms deck is located one level\ndown. I'll need a key card, but I should be able to find one\nin the nearby operator rooms.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nFind a key card to access the lower levels."
"02_02b" "  ARMSTRONG: Where the hell do all these Velians keep coming\nfrom? It's just damn lucky they didn't modify this part of the\nbase into their sick alien biomess they usually live in.\nI've seen pictures of that nightmare and they're just too creepy.\nOf course, that nightmare is my future. If I survive this.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nContinue through the lower levels to the communication deck."

"02_03a" "  ARMSTRONG: I'm at the entrance to the living quarters.\nJust below this section there should be a hypercommunications\ndevice that I can use to contact Admiral Parker at headquarters.\nHe'll want to know what happened to Horst and the Varyag\nCruiser. I have the distinct feeling he's gonna be pissed.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nMove through the living quarters."
"02_03b" " "
"02_03c" "  ARMSTRONG: Finally! The communications terminal should be\njust around the corner. Where do these Velians keep coming\nfrom? They must be sending reinforcements every few hours.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nGet to the hypercommunications terminal and establish uplink."
"02_03d" "  ARMSTRONG: Okay, I've keyed the terminal's frequency into my\npersonal communicator. I should now be able to get a message\nto H.Q. But first, I need to get the hell off this level. There\nare too many Velians around here and I need some time to\nexplain all that has happened.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nGet to the transport system, then contact H.Q."

"02_04a" "  PARKER: Armstrong! The fleet is engaged in battle with a wing\nof Velian fighters. I've managed to send one ship to pick you\nup. How soon can you make it to the exterior of the station?\n  ARMSTRONG: I'm at the subway terminal. Normally, it would be\nthe quickest route, but 10 to 1 it's locked down tight.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nFind a key card in one of the subway service areas."
"02_04b" "  ARMSTRONG: Now that the door is open I've just got to make\nit to the subway platform. After a train ride and zero gravity\nwalk I'll be out of this place. Hopefully Admiral Parker will gear\nup the troops for a full assault on the Velian planet. If\nhe won't, then I'll go myself. I owe Commander Horst that much.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nBoard the express train."

"02_05a" "  PARKER: Bad news, sergeant. The ship we sent to pick you up\ncame under attack from the station's main defenses. That place\nis more heavily fortified than we anticipated. Our reports\nindicate the other side of the station is virtually defenceless,\nso the ship will meet you on the safer side. Get to it!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nFind a key card and activate the deck-lift to the lower level."
"02_05b" "  PARKER: The Velian mechanoids re-inforced the other side of\nthe station and destroyed the rescue ship. However, our science\ndivision has intercepted sensor data indicating there is\na matter transportation device on that other side.\n  ARMSTRONG: I understand, sir. I'll find it. I don't have a choice.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nMove through the external deck to the other station section."

"02_06a" "  BRECHOV: This is professor Brechov, in charge of the science\ndivision. The Velians have adapted the architecture of the\nstation with biomass. We think it helps them breathe. Maybe.\nYou need to get to the central sphere using their transport\ntubes. They'll make you sick, but they work. Good luck, sergeant!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nFind a way inside the central sphere."

"02_07a" "  ARMSTRONG: What have they done to this place?\n  BRECHOV: We're not sure, but the walls are made from human\nD.N.A. The main thing is that we've confirmed the use of a\nZero-T transportation device. That's how they've been getting\nre-inforcements. Our scans reveal it is on a lower deck.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nGet to the lower decks."
"02_07b" "  BRECHOV: Okay, you're getting closer to the signal.\n  ARMSTRONG: Professor, how is the fleet doing back at H.Q.?\n  BRECHOV: Half of our fleet has been wiped out. We believe\nthe Zero-T in the space station may be to blame for the\nVelians' strength. And you are heading right for it.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nProceed to the lower decks and the Zero-T Device."

"02_08a" "  ARMSTRONG: Those transports are sickening.\n  BRECHOV: Keep going, you're almost there. We're working on a\nplan to put a permanent halt to the Velian re-inforcements.\n  ARMSTRONG: Am I involved? If so, just tell me what to do.\n  PARKER: Get to the device, I'll fill you in when you're closer.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nContinue toward the Zero-T Terminal."
"02_08b" "  BRECHOV: I've just made an astounding discovery thanks to\nyour H.U.D. sensory link-up. The fat Momos, otherwise known\nas Dirod Ballhands, are sustained with internal helium pouches,\nmaking them light. Even though you can easily push them around,\nI suggest you don't try to inhale them unless you have to.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nContinue toward the Zero-T Terminal."
"02_08c" " "
"02_08d" "  PARKER: When you activate the Zero-T, there will be a\nconnection between the station and headquarters. After you\ntransport out we're going to transport in a molecular bomb.\nYou must clear the target area of Velians. Understand?\n  ARMSTRONG: Yes, sir! See you soon, sir!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nGo through the tunnel and enter the Zero-T portal."

"03_01a" "  ARMSTRONG: If the fleet attacked now the colonists would be\nkilled, so I've volunteered to go alone, before we strike back.\nThe Velians don't see one man as a threat to a whole planet.\nMaybe they're right, but this one man still has a score to settle.\nI will save Horst's daughter and rescue the colonists. For Horst!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nGo to the mine entrance check-point."
"03_01b" "  PARKER: We've got new scans of the base. There are multiple\nhuman life-signs collected around what Brechov believes is a\ncryochamber and body harvesting facility. It's about 5 levels\ndown and drawing so much power, it has to be the central core.\n  ARMSTRONG: Don't worry, sir. I'll find it and shut it down.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nFind a way into the main underground base."

"03_02a" "  BRECHOV: This part of the mining facility was mostly\nabandoned when the lower levels were turned into a research\nbase in 2149. You'll need to get to that section. It's where the\nVelians have all swarmed to. You'll also need an access card.\n  ARMSTRONG: Okay, I've located a key card with my scanner.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nPick up the key card from the power plant."
"03_02b" "  PARKER: Armstrong, I'm giving you this heads up. Now that\nthe Velian re-inforcements have been taken care of, we have\nour chance to strike. The fleet is now mobilizing. We will be\nmaking planetfall in 26 hours. You have until then to finish\nyour mission. You'll soon be out of comms range, so good luck!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nEnter the Velian reproduction center."
"03_02c" "  ARMSTRONG: This key's hard-coded to a maintenance room\nnearby. There must be something in there that can re-activate\nsome of this machinery.\n  BRECHOV: Mmm, yes. Good idea. I'm analysing the readings from\nyour scanner. The pulses from the level below are remarkable!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nUnlock the maintenance room and power up the systems."
"03_02d" "  ARMSTRONG: I'm on my way, Brechov. Any useful info for me?\n  BRECHOV: The level below you seems to be some kind of... farm.\nIt's Where the Velians grow their soldiers, weaponry, everything.\nThe entrance is behind a conveyor belt in the main loading bay.\nBe careful. They are tracking you and trying to block our signal.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nOpen up the way to the Velian farm."

"03_03a" "  ARMSTRONG: Well I've lost contact with H.Q. I guess I'm on my\nown from here on out. I'm just going to follow my scanner's\nenergy readings. That will eventually lead me to the main\ncryochamber. I'll be able to shut down the power grid and finally\nreturn this necklace to Horst's daughter, if she's still alive.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nGo through the central bioprocessor."
"03_03b" " "

"03_04a" "  HORST: Armstrong, can you hear me? This is Commander Horst.\n  ARMSTRONG: Commander? But... I saw you die! The Varyag...\n  HORST: There's no time for explanations now, Armstrong. The\nVelians have captured some of our armored space-suits. Go find\none! Quickly! Then we'll talk more.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nFind the captured armored space-suit."
"03_04b" "  ARMSTRONG: What about the missing colonists?\n  HORST: They are safe. The Velians don't want to hurt anyone.\nNow, you need to return to headquarters and inform command\nthat the Velians are peaceful. They want to be our friends!\n  ARMSTRONG: Hell no, sir. I'm gonna rescue the colonists!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nUse the armored space-suit to make your way to the exit."
"03_04c" "  HORST: Good! Now get yourself a flight-pack and you can get\nout of here! I'm safe, don't worry about me. Everything is fine!\n  ARMSTRONG: Where are you? How did you get off the Varyag?\n  HORST: The Velians rescued me, patched me up and reunited\nme with my daughter. They want to make peace with us, you know.\n  OBJECTIVE:\nFind a flight-pack for the armored suit."

"03_05a" "  HORST: Do not go any further, Armstrong, that's an order!\n  ARMSTRONG: Enough! You are not Commander Horst.\n  HORST: Yes I am. The Velians recovered my body before the\nship exploded, then revived me here. Now I work for them.\n  ARMSTRONG: Lies! Whoever you are, I'm gonna make you pay!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nContinue searching for the main cryoroom."

"03_06a" "  MATRIARCH: You made it. Here at last, Armstrong.\n  ARMSTRONG: So you're not hiding behind Horst's voice any more.\n  MATRIARCH: You have good genetic material, Armstrong.\nPerhaps I'll use you as the basis for a new kind of battle golem...\nor maybe I'll take your skin as my own!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nCollect supplies for the Velian battle suit, then unlock it."
"03_06b" "  MATRIARCH: You will be turned into raw materials,\nArmstrong! You and all your pulpy, fleshy race!\n  ARMSTRONG: No. I'm going to save the colonists and\nCommander Horst's daughter! It's time for you to die!\n  OBJECTIVE:\nDestroy the Matriarch."
